Guide to the United Federation of Teachers Records WAG.022
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: President's Files
  - Subseries II:B: UFT Presidential Files of Albert Shanker, 1935-1996.
    - Elementary Education: Reports, 1969-1981 (Box 61, Folder 17)
    - Elementary School Issues, 1965-1975 (Box 61, Folder 18)
    - Elementary School Principals Association, 1965-1974 (Box 61, Folder 19)
    - Eleven-Month School Year Program, 1967 (Box 61, Folder 20)
    - Emergency Financial Control Board: NYS Legislature Bill, 1975 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Emergency Financial Control Board, 1975-1978 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Emergency Financial Control Board, 1976 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Emergency Financial Control Board, 1976 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Emergency Financial Control Board, 1977 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Emergency Financial Control Board, 1977 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Emergency Financial Control Board, 1977-1978 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Emergency Financial Control Board, 1978 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Emergency School Aid Act, 1973-1974 (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Emergency School Aid Act: Correspondence, 1973-1980 (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - Emergency School Aid Act: ESAA Committee, 1973 (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - Emergency School Aid Act: Ineligible School Districts, 1977 (Box 62, Folder 12)
    - Emergency School Aid Act: Project Testing, 1973 (Box 62, Folder 13)
    - Emergency School Aid Act: Reports, 1972-1978 (Box 62, Folder 14)
    - Empire State Federation of Teachers, 1967-1968 (Box 62, Folder 15)
    - Empire State Federation of Teachers, 1967-1970 (Box 62, Folder 16)
    - Empire State Federation of Teachers: Meeting Minutes, 1967-1970 (Box 62, Folder 17)
    - Empire State Federation of Teachers: Zeluck Decision, 1969-1971 (Box 62, Folder 18)
    - Environment: Students for Environmental Action, 1970 (Box 62, Folder 19)
    - EQUAL - Community Education Program, 1966-1968 (Box 62, Folder 20)
    - Equal Retirement, Committee for, 1966 (Box 62, Folder 21)
    - Ethnicity, 1972-1973 (Box 62, Folder 22)
    - Ethnicity, 1974-1976 (Box 62, Folder 23)
    - Ethnicity: HEW Survey, 1975-1976 (Box 62, Folder 24)
    - Examination Procedures/Complaints, 1965-1971 (Box 62, Folder 25)
    - Excessing, 1974-1978 (Box 62, Folder 26)
    - Experimental Programs (Special Service Schools), Committee on, 1968 (Box 62, Folder 27)
    - Extra Curricular Activities Committee/Per Session, 1966-1979 (Box 62, Folder 28)
    - Federal Aid, 1967-1979 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Feldman, Sandra: Visit to Japan, 1978 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Feldman, Sandra: Visit to Japan, 1978 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Ferguson's Castle, 1966 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Financial Reports, 1962-1966 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Financial Reports, 1967-1971 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Financial Reports, 1973-1977 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Financial Reports, 1975-1976 (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Financial Reports, 1976-1981 (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Fiscal Crisis, 1975 (Box 63, Folder 10)
    - Fiscal Crisis, 1975 (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - Fiscal Crisis, 1976-1979 (Box 63, Folder 12)
    - Fiscal Crisis, 1979-1980 (Box 63, Folder 13)
    - Fiscal Crisis: Budget Cuts, 1975 (Box 63, Folder 14)
    - Fiscal Crisis: Correspondence, 1975 (Box 63, Folder 15)
    - Fiscal Crisis: House Banking Committee, 1975 (Box 63, Folder 16)
    - Fiscal Crisis: Municipal Assistance Bills, 1975 (Box 63, Folder 17)
    - Fiscal Crisis: NYC Employee Retirement System, 1975 (Box 63, Folder 18)
    - Fiscal Crisis: Reports, AFT, 1975 (Box 63, Folder 19)
    - Fiscal Crisis: Reports, Congressional, 1975 (Box 63, Folder 20)
    - Fiscal Crisis: Reports, NYC and NYS, 1975 (Box 63, Folder 21)
    - Fiscal Crisis: Reports, NYSUT, 1975 (Box 63, Folder 22)
    - Fiscal Crisis: Social Security Withdrawal Proposal, 1975 (Box 63, Folder 23)
    - Fiscal Crisis: UFT Purchase of MAC Bonds, 1975 (Box 63, Folder 24)
    - Fiscal Crisis: Wage Freezes, 1975 (Box 63, Folder 25)
    - Fleischmann Commission: Study on the quality, cost, and financing of Elementary and Secondary Education in NY State., 1972-1973 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Forced Transfers, 1965 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Ford, President Gerald, 1974-1975 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Ford Foundation, 1967-1979 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Ford Foundation - Publications, 1964-1979 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Ford Foundation/Fordham University Special Training Program for Urban School Administrators, 1967 (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Fordham University, 1966-1977 (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Foreign Affairs, 1973-1985 (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Freedom House, 1970-1978 (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Freedom Schools, 1963-1965 (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Frontlash, 1972 (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - Fuccillo, George, 1968 (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - Full Employment Action Council, 1975-1978 (Box 64, Folder 13)
    - Fundamental Adult Education, 1975 (Box 64, Folder 14)
    - Funding, 1970-1972 (Box 64, Folder 15)
    - Funding, 1973-1977 (Box 64, Folder 16)
    - Funding, 1978-1980 (Box 64, Folder 17)
    - Gay Civil Rights, 1969-1975 (Box 64, Folder 18)
    - Gay Teachers Association, 1974-1979 (Box 64, Folder 19)
    - Gelertner, Sandy, 1964-1971 (Box 64, Folder 20)
    - General Electric Strike, 1969-1970 (Box 64, Folder 21)
    - Ghetto Schools Plans, 1966-1967 (Box 64, Folder 22)
    - Ghetto Schools Proposal, 1966 (Box 64, Folder 23)
    - Gifted Students: "Centering on the Gifted" - presented to NYC Teacher Centers Consortium, 1980 (Box 64, Folder 24)
    - Gordon, Dr. Edmund, 1968-1969 (Box 64, Folder 25)
    - Gordon, Reuben, 1965-1975 (Box 64, Folder 26)
    - Gotbaum, Victor, 1979-1982 (Box 64, Folder 27)
    - Grievances, 1963-1966 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Grievances, 1973-1975 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Grievances, 1976-1978 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Grievances, 1979 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Grievances, 1980 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Grievances - Roy Longarzo, 1973-1980 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Guidance Counselors, 1963-1968 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Guidance Counselors, 1969-1975 (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Guidance Counselors, 1976-1977 (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - Guidance Counselors Chapter, 1966-1979 (Box 65, Folder 10)
    - Harvard University, 1966-1969 (Box 65, Folder 11)
    - Head Start, 1964-1977 (Box 65, Folder 12)
    - Health Education Teachers Association (HETA), 1965-1968 (Box 65, Folder 13)
    - Health, Education and Welfare Dept. (HEW), 1968-1974 (Box 65, Folder 14)
    - Health, Education and Welfare Dept .(HEW), 1975-1979 (Box 65, Folder 15)
    - Health, Education and Welfare Dept. (HEW): Caulfield Case, 1977-1979 (Box 65, Folder 16)
    - Health, Education and Welfare Dept. (HEW): Caulfield Case, 1979 (Box 65, Folder 17)
    - Health, Education and Welfare Dept. (HEW): Issue of Discrimination, 1976-1979 (Box 65, Folder 18)
    - Health, Education and Welfare Dept.: School Finance Project, 1980 (Box 65, Folder 19)
    - High School Organization Report, 1963 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - High School Principals Association, 1969-1972 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - High Schools, 1966-1979 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - High Schools, 1980-1981 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - High Schools, 1982 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - High Schools: "600" Schools, 1964-1970 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - High Schools: Adams HS, 1971-1974 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - High Schools: Art and Design, HS of, 1968-1982 (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - High Schools: Aviation HS, 1970-1979 (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - High Schools: Bay Ridge HS, 1973-1975 (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - High Schools: Bayside HS, 1967-1977 (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - High Schools: Bowne HS, 1968-1974 (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - High Schools: Boys and Girls HS, 1977-1982 (Box 66, Folder 13)
    - High Schools: Brandeis HS, 1966-1980 (Box 66, Folder 14)
    - High Schools: Bronx High Schools/Miscellaneous, 1966-1976 (Box 66, Folder 15)
    - High Schools: Bronx HS of Science, 1969-1971 (Box 66, Folder 16)
    - High Schools: Brooklyn High Schools/Miscellaneous, 1965-1978 (Box 66, Folder 17)
    - High Schools: Brooklyn High Schools/Miscellaneous, 1966-1977 (Box 66, Folder 18)
    - High Schools: Brooklyn High Schools/Miscellaneous, 1968-1977 (Box 66, Folder 19)
    - High Schools: Cardozo HS, 1971-1972 (Box 66, Folder 20)
    - High Schools: Franklin HS, 1966-1982 (Box 66, Folder 21)
    - High Schools: Jackson HS, 1967-1981 (Box 66, Folder 22)
    - High Schools: Jamaica HS, 1967-1973 (Box 66, Folder 23)
    - High Schools: Lane (Franklin K.) HS, 1966-1982 (Box 66, Folder 24)
    - High Schools: Madison HS, 1966-1972 (Box 66, Folder 25)
    - High Schools: Manhattan High Schools/Miscellaneous, 1965-1976 (Box 66, Folder 26)
    - High Schools: Martin (August) HS, 1970-1973 (Box 66, Folder 27)
    - High Schools: Private Schools, 1964-1978 (Box 66, Folder 28)
    - High Schools: Problem Schools, 1964-1977 (Box 66, Folder 29)
    - High Schools: Queens High Schools/Miscellaneous, 1966-1976 (Box 66, Folder 30)
    - High Schools: Seward Park HS, 1965-1974 (Box 66, Folder 31)
    - High Schools: Van Buren HS, 1967-1975 (Box 66, Folder 32)
    - High Schools: Vocational High Schools, 1964-1967 (Box 66, Folder 33)
    - High Schools: Vocational High Schools, 1970-1980 (Box 66, Folder 34)
    - High Schools: Washington HS, 1969-1976 (Box 66, Folder 35)
    - Hispanic Labor Committee, 1973-1979 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Hiss, Alger, 1976 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Histadrut, 1967-1979 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Homebound Teachers, 1967-1976 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Homebound Teachers, 1977-1979 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Homosexuals in NYC Schools, 1974 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Honest Ballot Association, 1965-1970 (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Honest Ballot Association: 1966 and 1970 UFT Ballots (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Honest Ballot Association: UFT Election Certificates, 1963-1972 (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - Hopkins, Ned (Asst. to President), 1972-1976 (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - Hopkins, Ned (Asst. to President), 1975 (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - Hotel Sonesta, 1969 (Box 67, Folder 12)
    - House Un-American Activities Committee, 1966-1968 (Box 67, Folder 13)
    - Housing, 1965-1971 (Box 67, Folder 14)
    - Howe, Irving, 1968-1974 (Box 67, Folder 15)
    - Human Relations Work-Study Center, 1975 (Box 67, Folder 16)
    - Human Resources Administration, 1969-1977 (Box 67, Folder 17)
    - Human Rights, Commission on, 1967-1978 (Box 67, Folder 18)
    - Human Rights and Genocide Treaties, Ad Hoc Committee on, 1966-1971 (Box 67, Folder 19)
    - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1968-1978 (Box 67, Folder 20)
    - Humphrey/Hawkins Full Employment and Growth Act, 1976-1978 (Box 67, Folder 21)
    - ILGWU, 1969-1979 (Box 67, Folder 22)
    - Income Tax, UFT, 1965-1977 (Box 67, Folder 23)
    - Indiana University, 1967-1975 (Box 67, Folder 24)
    - Inflation: Labor Summit, 1974 (Box 67, Folder 25)
    - Institute for World Order, 1975 (Box 67, Folder 26)
    - Insurance: Health and Auto, 1963-1982 (Box 67, Folder 27)
    - Integration, 1964 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Integration: UFT Meeting Transcript, 1964 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Integration, 1965-1977 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - International Federation of Free Teachers' Unions, 1971-1972 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - International Federation of Free Teachers' Unions, 1973-1974 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - International Federation of Free Teachers' Unions, 1975-1976 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - International Federation of Free Teachers' Unions, 1977-1979 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - International Federation of Free Teachers' Unions: Newsletters, 1972-1975 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - International Foundation of Employee Benefit Plans, 1974-1976 (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - International Rescue Committee, 1973-1975 (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - International Rescue Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - International Rescue Committee, 1978 (Box 68, Folder 12)
    - International Rescue Committee, 1979 (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - International Rescue Committee: Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 68, Folder 14)
    - Interracial Colloquy: Selection of Supervisory Personnel, 1971 (Box 68, Folder 15)
    - Interviews, 1974-1983 (Box 68, Folder 16)
    - Island Trees School District: Supreme Court Case, 1981 (Box 68, Folder 17)
    - Israel, 1971-1980 (Box 68, Folder 18)
    - Israel Teachers Union, 1971-1976 (Box 68, Folder 19)
    - Jail Sentence (Shanker), 1967 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Japan: Communist Party, 1970-1973 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Japan: Elections, 1971-1972 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Japan: Labor, Workmen's Comp, Severance, 1972-1974 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Japan: Shanker Trip, 1974 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Japan: Teacher Training, 1973 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Japanese Teachers Union, 1964-1979 (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Javits, Senator Jacob, 1967-1981 (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Jencks, Christopher, 1972-1973 (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - Jewish Daily Forward, 1969-1981 (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - Jewish Defense League, 1969-1972 (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - Jewish Labor Committee, 1971-1972 (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - Jewish Labor Committee, 1973-1979 (Box 69, Folder 13)
    - Jewish Labor Council: Student Committee, 1966-1967 (Box 69, Folder 14)
    - Jewish Teachers Association, 1967-1977 (Box 69, Folder 15)
    - Jewish Teachers Community Chest, 1966-1977 (Box 69, Folder 16)
    - Jewish Teachers, Association of Orthodox (AOJT), 1966-1979 (Box 69, Folder 17)
    - Joint Council on Economic Education, 1966-1979 (Box 69, Folder 18)
    - Junior High Schools, 1962-1973 (Box 69, Folder 19)
    - Karelsen, Lawrence and Nathan, 1966-1978 (Box 69, Folder 20)
    - Kennedy, Senator Robert F.: Correspondence, 1965-1968 (Box 69, Folder 21)
    - Keyserling, Leon H., 1967-1978 (Box 69, Folder 22)
    - King, Martin Luther, Jr., 1963-1979 (Box 69, Folder 23)
    - Kingsport Press Strike, 1966 (Box 69, Folder 24)
    - Klepak, Dan (Director, NYS Office of Education): Reports, 1974 (Box 69, Folder 25)
    - Koch, Mayor Edward, 1973-1978 (Box 69, Folder 26)
    - Koppersmith, Hal, 1962-1971 (Box 69, Folder 27)
    - Kowtuniuk, Filimon, 1974 (Box 69, Folder 28)
    - Kraus, Arthur James, 1971-1972 (Box 69, Folder 29)
    - Krupsak, Lt. Gov. Mary Anne, 1975-1976 (Box 69, Folder 30)
    - Lab Specialists, 1966-1979 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Labor Council for Latin American Advancement, 1974-1976 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Labor Council for Latin American Advancement: Progress Report, 1974-1975 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Labor Council for Latin American Advancement: Voter Registration/GOTV, 1976 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Labor Theater, 1973-1976 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - LaRouche, Lyndon, 1974-1982 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - LaRouche, Lyndon: National Caucus of Labor Committees, 1974-1976 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - LaRouche, Lyndon: New Solidarity, 1972-1979 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - LaRouche, Lyndon: Our Town(Manhattan Newspaper), opposition, 1979-1981 (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - LaRouche, Lyndon: U.S. Labor Party, 1974-1981 (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - Lass, Abraham: Correspondence, 1972 (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - Lass, Abraham: Memoranda, 1972 (Box 70, Folder 12)
    - Lass, Abraham - Richard Safran: Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 70, Folder 13)
    - LBJ Library Symposium on "Great Society" Programs, 1976 (Box 70, Folder 14)
    - League for Industrial Democracy, 1964-1967 (Box 70, Folder 15)
    - League for Industrial Democracy, 1968-1981 (Box 70, Folder 16)
    - Leaves/Miscellaneous, 1966-1982 (Box 70, Folder 17)
    - Leaves of Absence: Sick Leaves, 1964-1966 (Box 70, Folder 18)
    - Lecture Series: Shanker- Restructuring Education, 1971 (Box 70, Folder 19)
    - Lectures: Wide World Lecture Bureau, 1969-1970 (Box 70, Folder 20)
    - Legal: Cases and Opinions, 1965-1976 (Box 70, Folder 21)
    - Legal: Sabath vs. Shanker, 1972 (Box 70, Folder 22)
    - Legal: UFT vs. Board of Education, 1971 (Box 70, Folder 23)
    - Legal: UFT/Board of Education Arbitration, 1965 (Box 70, Folder 24)
    - Legal Issues, 1964-1966 (Box 70, Folder 25)
    - Legal Issues, 1967-1969 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Legal Issues, 1970-1971 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Legal Issues, 1972-1974 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Legal Issues, 1976-1978 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Legislation, 1966-1967 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Legislation, 1968-1970 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Legislation, 1971-1972 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Legislative: General, 1965-1975 (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Levittown Case, 1975-1978 (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Levittown Case, 1978-1982 (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Levittown Case: Decision - Levittown vs. Nyquist, 1978 (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - Levittown Case: Special Task Force in Equity and Excellence in Education (Rubin Commission), 1976-1979 (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - Levittown Case: Special Task Force in Equity and Excellence in Education (Rubin Commission), 1980 (Box 71, Folder 13)
    - Levittown Case: Special Task Force in Equity and Excellence in Education (Rubin Commission), 1980 (Box 71, Folder 14)
    - Levittown Case: Special Task Force in Equity and Excellence in Education (Rubin Commission), 1980-1981 (Box 71, Folder 15)
    - Levittown Case: Special Task Force in Equity and Excellence in Education (Rubin Commission), 1981 (Box 71, Folder 16)
    - Levittown Case: Special Task Force in Equity and Excellence in Education (Rubin Commission), 1981-1982 (Box 71, Folder 17)
    - Levittown Case: Special Task Force in Equity and Excellence in Education (Rubin Commission), 1981-1982 (Box 71, Folder 18)
    - Levittown United Teachers Strike, 1978-1979 (Box 71, Folder 19)
    - Liberal Party, 1964-1968 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Licensing, 1973-1979 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Lieberman, Myron: Correspondence, 1964-1971 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Lieberman, Myron: Correspondence, 1972-1975 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Lieberman, Myron: Phi Delta Kappan, 1961-1975 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Lieberman, Myron: Writings and Vita, 1958-1972 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Life Insurance, 1965-1977 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Lindsay for Mayor, 1965 (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Lindsay, Mayor John, 1965-1973 (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Lists and Names: General, 1969-1982 (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Lists of Periodicals/Journals Saved by A. Shanker (through 10/6/82), 1982 (Box 72, Folder 11)
    - Local 1199, Hospital Employees Union, 1967-1969 (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - Local 1199: Collective Bargaining Campaign, 1980 (Box 72, Folder 13)
    - Local Union Equal Employment, 1967-1974 (Box 72, Folder 14)
    - Loiacono, Charles, 1970 (Box 72, Folder 15)
    - Lora Decree, 1979-1980 (Box 72, Folder 16)
    - Loyalty Oath, 1966-1977 (Box 72, Folder 17)
    - Lubin, Alan (District #16 Representative - Brooklyn), 1969-1970 (Box 72, Folder 18)
    - Lubin, Alan: Decentralization - Local School Board Elections, 1969-1970 (Box 72, Folder 19)
    - Lutheran Medical Center, 1979-1983 (Box 72, Folder 20)
    - Lutheran Medical Center Negotiations, 1979-1980 (Box 72, Folder 21)
    - Lutheran Medical Center Negotiations, 1979-1980 (Box 72, Folder 22)
    - Malpractice, 1970-1975 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Manhattan Borough Office, 1970-1977 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Manpower Development Training Program, 1966-1978 (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Marland, Sidney P., 1970-1981 (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Marsh, Alice, 1969-1977 (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Maternity Leave Policies, 1974-1978 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - McGovern, George, 1972 (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - McGovern, George: Labor Support and Opposition, 1972 (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Meeting House Foundation, 1971-1976 (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Meeting House Foundation: Legal, 1971-1976 (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Membership: Teachers Guild and Early UFT (Pre-Shanker), 1958-1963 (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - Membership: Member Counts and Applicants Submitting Check Off Cards, 1966-1967 (Box 73, Folder 12)
    - Membership Drive, Teachers and Paras, 1973 (Box 73, Folder 13)
    - Membership Reports, 1972-1984 (Box 73, Folder 14)
    - Membership Services, 1974-1982 (Box 73, Folder 15)
    - Memphis Sanitation Fund, 1968 (Box 73, Folder 16)
    - Mental Health: Dept of Mental Health Report (NYC), 1977-78 Component of 1976-80 Plan (Box 73, Folder 17)
    - Mental Health Workers, 1973-1974 (Box 73, Folder 18)
    - Merit Pay, 1985 (Box 73, Folder 19)
    - Metropolitan Urban Service Training (MUST), 1966 (Box 73, Folder 20)
    - Montauk Manor, 1967-1968 (Box 73, Folder 21)
    - More Effective Schools (MES), 1964-1965 (Box 73, Folder 22)
    - More Effective Schools (MES), 1966-1967 (Box 73, Folder 23)
    - More Effective Schools (MES), 1966-1967 (Box 73, Folder 24)
    - More Effective Schools (MES), 1968-1969 (Box 73, Folder 25)
    - More Effective Schools (MES), 1970 (Box 73, Folder 26)
    - More Effective Schools (MES), 1971-1976 (Box 73, Folder 27)
    - More Effective Schools (MES), undated (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - More Effective Schools (MES): Articles, 1965-1968 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - More Effective Schools (MES): Beagle, Simon, 1965-1968 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - More Effective Schools (MES): Board of Education Evaluation, 1966-1968 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - More Effective Schools (MES): Correspondence, 1965-1971 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - More Effective Schools (MES): Data and Evaluations, 1965-1968 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - More Effective Schools (MES): Ghetto References, ca.1967 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - More Effective Schools (MES): Legislative Bills, 1967-1968 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - More Effective Schools (MES): Other Cities, 1965-1968 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - More Effective Schools (MES): Printed Materials, 1964-1972 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - More Effective Schools (MES): Reading Scores, 1966-1967 (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - More Effective Schools (MES): UFT Analysis of MES, 1963-1967 (Box 74, Folder 12)
    - Moskow, Michael, 1967-1974 (Box 74, Folder 13)
    - Municipal Credit Union, 1977-1979 (Box 74, Folder 14)
    - Municipal Labor Committee, 1970-1979 (Box 74, Folder 15)
    - Municipal Union/Financial Leaders Group, 1977-1979 (Box 74, Folder 16)
    - NAACP, 1967-1981 (Box 74, Folder 17)
    - Narcotics, 1969-1971 (Box 74, Folder 18)
    - Narcotics, 1970-1972 (Box 74, Folder 19)
    - Narcotics, 1971-1975 (Box 74, Folder 20)
    - National Advisory Committee on Urban Education, 1968-1972 (Box 74, Folder 21)
    - National Center for the Study of Collective Bargaining in Higher Education, 1972 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - National Center for the Study of Collective Bargaining in Higher Education, 1973 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - National Coalition for Teacher Unity, 1973-1974 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - National Committee for Citizens in Education, 1974 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - National Council of Churches, 1967-1973 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - National Council of Urban Education Associations: Correspondence, 1972-1975 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - National Council of Urban Education Associations: Minutes, 1972-1974 (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - National Education Association (NEA), 1969-1977 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - National Education Association (NEA), 1978-1979 (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - National Education Association (NEA), 1982-1987 (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - National Education Association (NEA): AFT Merger, 1965-1973 (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - National Education Association (NEA): AFT Merger, 1974-1981 (Box 75, Folder 12)
    - National Education Association (NEA): Collective Bargaining, 1970-1977 (Box 75, Folder 13)
    - National Education Association (NEA): Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 75, Folder 14)
    - National Education Association (NEA): NYC Organizing Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 75, Folder 15)
    - National Education Association (NEA): NYC Organizing Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 75, Folder 16)
    - National Education Association (NEA): NYC Organizing Committee - Minutes, 1976-1977 (Box 75, Folder 17)
    - National Education Association (NEA): NYC Organizing Committee - Publicity, 1976-1977 (Box 75, Folder 18)
    - National Education Association (NEA): New York Educators Association, 1976-1979 (Box 75, Folder 19)